David McGowan

Web and Mobile Developer.

26 Harelaw Avenue, Glasgow, G44 3HZ dmcportfolio.co.uk david@dmcportfolio.co.uk uk.linkedin.com/in/davidmcg1985 07581 065547 / 0141 637 5872

DOB - 10th June 1985

Education

The University of the West of Scotland

Web and Mobile Development BSc Hons, 2013 - 2016

I began studying Web and Mobile Development at UWS after completing a one year HNC at college. I progressed on to my honours year and I am on course to graduate with a first class award. The modules completed were:

- Database Development
- HTML5 and JavaScript **Programming**
- Object Oriented Analysis
- · Programming for Mobile Devices
- · Computing Project
- Computing Honours Project Server Side Systems
- Dynamic Web Technologies
 Database Applications
- Internet Technologies

- · Professionalism in the **Creative Technologies**
- Web Site Development
- Internet Scripting
- · Web Server Technology
- · Advanced Programming for Mobile Devices

I am currently developing a photo sharing web application for my technical honours project. The application will use the Django Python framework and a PostgreSQL database. The main concept of the application is for users to share photographs that can then be adapted and redistrubuted under the Creative Commons license.

The City of Glasgow College

Interactive Media HNC, 2012 - 201.

Grade achieved: A

Work Experience

Aims Media (Work Experience)

Web Designer, Feb 2014 - April 2014

Involved working with designers on various WordPress projects. I was also tasked with creating email marketing campaigns while in regular contact with clients.

Webster Power Products

Website Manager, Sep 2011 - August 2012

Independently maintaing a Joomla e-commerce website which involved product management and order processing. Regular meetings with web developers to discuss website enhancements sparked an interest in the more technical aspect of web development.

The Saw Centre Ltd

Website Manager, Sep 2006 - Sep 2011

Mantaining an e-commerce website while working towards both team and individual sales targets. I also designed most promotional leaflets and banners for the company using InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator.

About Me

My experience combined with the skills I have gained at university have helped me understand projects from both a client and developers perspective. I am focused on expanding my skillset and strive to learn new languages and technologies in my own personal time.

Over the last 12 months I have taken a keen interest in MVC frameworks, in particular Django.

Technical Skills

Throughout my education and in my personal time I have continued to further enhance my technical skillsets.

Adobe Packages	•	•	•	•	0	0	0
AngularJS	•	O	•	0	0	0	0
Apache Web Server	•	•	•	•	0	0	0
ASP.NET / ASP.NET MVC	•	•	•	•	0	0	0
Bootstrap	•	•	•	•	•	•	0
C#	•	•	•	•	0	0	0
CSS	O	•	•	•	•	•	0
Django Framework	•	O	•	•	•	•	0
Git / Github / BitBucket	•	•	•	•	•	0	0
Google App Engine	•	•	•	•	•	0	0
Heroku	•	•	•	•	•	0	0
HTML5	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
JavaScript/jQuery	•	•	•	•	•	0	0
MySQL / PostgreSQL	•	•	•	•	0	0	0
PHP	•	•	•	•	0	0	0
Python	•	•	•	•	•	•	0
T-SQL	•	O	•	•	0	0	0
Wordpress	•	o	•	•	•	•	0

Personal Skills

- · Quality performer who strives for high standards and high work rate.
- Excellent communication skills which are continually developing through experience.
- · Hard working and thrives on being part of a team or working individually.
- Flexible and reliable individual who enjoys new challenges.
- Good listener, keen to learn and implement new skills.
- Mature and methodical approach towards work.

Personal Interests

I enjoy keeping active through playing football, running, cycling and the occasional munro climb. I have a keen passion for travelling. I have traveled extensively in Europe and would like to continue my travels in South-East Asia where I love the culture and in particular the food.